I'm sorry...
Why are you crying?
Because I left you alone...
You did?
Because I couldn't find
you for all this time...
But... I'm right here.
What's your name?
My name is...
I know this is just a dream world,
but I can smell the wind
and even feel the dirt.
It's so strange, isn't it?
Echidna? Are you listening?
I'm sorry! Are you all right?
Was I walking too quickly?
Did you think such transparent sympathy
would change my attitude in the least?
You're quite foolish, if so.
Oh, please. I was just worried about you.
I need none of your concern whatsoever.
There were a few too many dreams
happening at once, that's all.
It will adjust itself soon.
Just like this.
See?
"Dream world" is merely
a figurative expression.
More accurately, it's a separate
world that replicates the memories
and reflects the consciousness
of those who undergo the trial.
Thank you for explaining it so clearly,
even though you hate me.
Just don't go getting any silly ideas
about me actually being a very nice person.
It's simply my nature to answer
any questions asked of me.
Yes, of course.
Do you remember the pathetic struggle you
endured the last time you attempted the trial?
I was so helpless, I can't even argue
with that mean description of it.
I must have covered up my memories
because I didn't want to see them.
That's why I can't recall them on my own.
And even now,
I'm still not prepared.
So it would be no surprise
if you failed again?
Creating a line of defense before you
even start is awfully defeatist.
No, it's not that.
I'm going to prepare myself right now.
This is no ordinary tree, is it?
There was something you desperately
wanted to keep locked up inside it.
This is the Princess Room.
I was sent to play here
often when I was little.
Oh, right... I can't touch the door.
Can we just walk through it?
That young one is you, right?
Even considering you knew nothing yet,
you look so irritatingly carefree.
Must you even complain
about my younger self?
Besides, now I...
Mother Fortuna...
Emilia, I need to go take
care of something important.
So stay in this room and be good, all right?
"Something important" again?
You have my brother's silver hair...
But your kind features
come from your mother.
Everyone in my family has mean eyes.
I like your eyes, Mother Fortuna!
Mother Fortuna was my
father's younger sister.
My real parents were too
busy to spend time with me,
so I was left in Mother Fortuna's care.
I'm so bored!
And Mother always tells me lying
and keeping secrets are wrong!
Right?!
I wish I could go outside.
A fairy?
Hey, no fair! Wait!
Mother Fortuna and everyone
else keeps secrets from me,
so we're even!
Sneaky, sneak...
Sneak...
You've all done so much for us.
And we have put you through so much trouble.
Well, that goes for both of us,
Geuse.
Also...
I know I ask this every time we meet,
but is the seal intact?
Don't worry. Nothing has changed.
If the worst were to happen,
I could never face my brother and sister.
You mean your brother... and his wife?
It's all right. I know.
But I must never forget the weight
of the responsibility I carry.
I don't want to abandon it or
see it only partway through.
Isn't the same true for you?
I...
I have nothing else, after all.
I suppose it's a different sense
of responsibility from yours.
Obsession, regret...
I'm only clinging to things that
might as well be delusions.
Thanks to the spirits,
the seasons don't change much in the forest,
but you continue to bring us
things like clothing and books.
We truly appreciate it.
Thank you, as always.
In truth, it is wrong to force all of you
to live in such inconvenience
in a place like this.
Don't call it "a place like this."
We love the forest, you know.
Fortuna-sama!
All of the items have been transferred.
Thank you, Archi.
You've grown even more dependable
as well, Archi-dono.
As part of the next generation
of forest dwellers,
I cannot be regarded as a novice forever.
I pray your good health will persist.
For the forest and the seal,
for your family, and for yourself, too.
Oh, yes... Just one last thing.
Is Emilia-sama in good health?
Don't worry.
Emilia is growing into a very good,
very healthy girl.
But... I'm sorry.
I can't let her meet you.
It's all right.
As long as Emilia-sama grows
up healthy, that's enough.
A sinner such as myself could
never dare to ask for more.
Bishop Romanée-Conti, are you ready?
Yes, I'm finished.
Let us sinners be on our way.
May we meet again soon, Fortuna-sama.
Even if no one else will say it,
we are grateful to you.
I really mean that.
Your words alone would surely carry me
through a hundred years of turmoil.
Fortuna-sama, are you tired?
Don't treat me like such an old lady.
I know I'm old compared
to a young boy like you,
but I'm still in very good shape!
Th-That wasn't what I meant at all!
I just thought this must be hard, when you
also have the duty of the forest dwellers...
Then perhaps I'll take advantage
of your kindness...
And let you handle the rest.
I need to go and free a little
princess who must be very bored.
What do I do? What do I do?
What do I do? What do—
What do I do? What do I do? What—
What do I do? What do I do?
What do I do? What do I do? What do I do?
Wow...
Emilia, are you awake?
Eep!
I-I'm awake!
B-But...
What?
Why are you so flustered?
Um... I-I'm sorry.
I spilled a bunch of my drawing ink.
Oh, dear...
Mother Fortuna, I...
Honestly, you worry too much, Emilia.
You don't need to be so afraid.
I'm not angry.
But you're not hurt, are you?
Mother?
Oh, it's nothing.
I just missed you so, so much.
Spoiled child...
Hey, Emilia...
I love you.
Perhaps the sights you had locked
deep within your heart have begun
to overlap with scenes from your
memories, little by little?
I'm surprised.
I thought you'd have some stinging
comments to make about Mother and me.
Even if that's what you thought,
I wouldn't recommend coming
out and saying so.
My opinion of you is already low enough,
and you're making it plummet further.
Oh, don't worry.
I won't tell anyone else about this.
For better or for worse,
his influence on you has
grown increasingly strong.
Really?
Thanks!
Anyway, now you've recalled
your mother, some people you knew,
and that so-called fairy...
Are you ready to face your past now?
No, not yet.
There are still important
memories I'm missing.
What more could there be?
The seal.
Come on, little fairy.
We're escaping again today.
Emilia, I'm coming in.
Eep!
What's the matter?
Wh-What about you, Archi?
What was it you needed?
Well, first, I brought some snacks for you.
They're nuts.
Eat these and be a good girl, all right?
Thank you...
Archi has been a real worrywart lately.
I need to be careful.
Sneaky, sneak...
Geuse's group is here again today.
I thought whatever they were
hiding would be more fun.
Mother and the rest are so weird.
Emilia has been so full of energy lately.
She always comes home with
her clothes all muddy.
That she is so healthy can
only be a good thing.
I'll bring as many new
clothes for her as I can.
I'm sorry if I seem to be demanding more
when you've already done so much.
Do you have adult clothes, too?
Yes, of course.
I'm sure we have something
that will look lovely on you.
Hey, I know we've known
each other a long time,
but when did you start
making jokes like that?
I only told what I feel to be the truth...
Was there something strange
about what I said?
Geuse, what is this?
Oh, I just remembered another time
when you seemed unhappy while talking to me,
and it was because you had a fever.
You don't feel warm right now...
Come on, that was decades ago!
Don't treat me like a child!
Honestly...
Stupid Geuse!
And stupid Archi, too!
So... is the seal still in place?
As always, yes.
It's very conscientious of you
to check on it every time.
That is my duty, after all.
The state of affairs outside the
forest is dubious at the moment.
Perhaps my concern is baseless,
but I wanted you to be aware.
I understand.
Please remain diligent.
For Emilia-sama, and for
the two of them, too.
Seal?
Yes, please!
A door?
What a strange sight.
This is... the seal.
This seal's existence... is why...
You found the answer?
This is the seal?
Some other guy saw my love letter
to the girl I like before she did.
My life is over.
You're way too damn depressed about this!
C'mon, get it together, man!
I never imagined Garfiel would be there,
waiting to settle the score...
You're always hitting on her
in front of people, anyway.
Why get so embarrassed just because
you put it in writing this time?
I'm prepared for her to just
brush it off any other time!
And that's exactly what always
happens, so it's fine then!
But I was being serious this time!
And it was literally a
late-night love letter.
The most embarrassing kind!
Don't worry, boss.
If anything, it made me wish
I could sponge off of your luck.
"In matters of love, follow the
lingdorn's example," as they say.
When you say that,
it sounds like you're instigating,
even if you're not!
It took Garfiel about an
hour when he went in,
so I guess it'll take her about that long.
If she's successful, yes.
Ow!
Try to take a hint for a change.
Ouch!
You're that oblivious to the mood,
and you call yourself a merchant?
That hurt even more than the forehead flick!
Anyway...
Shima-sama wants to talk to you, Barusu.
She wants to continue
last night's discussion.
What did you and Gran—
the old hag talk about?
There's no point in saying it over.
We all know you're a Granny's boy.
Mostly, she told me what happened
when you went into the graveyard.
Oh, really?
I had my hands full yesterday figuring
out how to deal with Garfiel.
We ended up putting off
the important part.
Just what did you put off?
Well...
A subject that is unavoidable if you
wish to liberate the Sanctuary.
Hngh... Hngh... Hngh...
Why won't it just fall over?
It's a little too weird
for me to understand.
But thanks to all of you,
I managed to find it!
Clap, clap, clap!
Hmph. It's all Mother Fortuna's fault.
And Geuse's fault.
Nyah!
All right, time to go home.
Today, the painter feels like coloring
the sky red and the forest white!
What's wrong?
Could it be... something's about to happen?
This is quite a problem.
I might not make it by the appointed time.
Oh? And whose cute little
behind might that be?
I implore you to grant me temperate mercy...
Well, well! What an adorable young lady—
A-Are you...
No, you couldn't be...
Geuse?
Are you all right?
I am... fine...
Yes... Yes! Of course I'm all right!
Nothing is wrong in the slightest!
Because I...
I... I have just...
been granted salvation like never before!
Really?
You got saved, but you're crying?
I'm not crying because I'm sad.
I'm so happy... I'm so overjoyed.
I'm so truly blessed...
And such happiness can bring
warm tears sometimes.
You cry... even when you're happy?
It's all right, Geuse.
It's all right.
I know there are so many things
like this that I'd forgotten...
But not too long ago, I wouldn't
have been able to accept this.
Still, right now...
I'm scared, but I won't cower in fear.
You're giving up on the decision to
depend on a man or father figure,
even though it's so typical
of a filthy woman like you?
I'm sure Subaru would
forgive me if I did that,
but I'd still be weak,
and I don't want to just shrug off that fact.
Besides...
I don't want all those things Subaru
wrote for me to end up being wrong.
Subaru believes in me,
and that's why I don't want to
be embarrassed by his feelings.
Do as you wish.
I will simply find satisfaction
in your suffering.
So everything is ready now?
Yes. The warm-up round is over.
The trial that broke you
once now begins for real.
Please wait, Emilia-sama!
It's dangerous to run around like that!
Nope! Nope!
Come on! Just try to catch me!
Her mischief is too much
for us to handle, too.
To have so much energy is a good thing.
I just... wish she would avoid
doing anything dangerous.
If she could just jump around in her home,
healthy and bathed in sunlight,
with no concerns about breaking anything...
Geuse...
That would be very difficult.
W-Would it?
But for Emilia-sama's sake, I just...
I just...
Hey!
Mother and Geuse! Why aren't
either of you chasing me?
Aren't we playing chase right now?!
Ah, please forgive me!
Never have I made such a terrible mistake!
Don't spoil her like that.
Emilia, come here.
What is it, Mother?
Honestly, you're so spoiled.
Eep!
Too bad!
You've been captured by Mother Fortuna!
No fair! That's cheating, Mother!
That's wrong! That's dirty! Say you're sorry!
Goodness, just listen to this girl!
Are you thinking about
what I said to you, then?
Why do you think Geuse
and I were chasing you?
N-No, Mother!
The fairies said we should
go outside and play, so I...
I don't like children who blame things
on other people—rather, fairies.
I'm sorry.
Since I made friends with Geuse,
I wanted to tell you about it.
And since Geuse is a crybaby,
I felt like I had to help him.
That feeling is very precious.
But we made a promise that you'd
never go to that place, didn't we?
Y-Yes... we did.
That was a very bad thing to do.
A promise is the embodiment of trust,
and to break it is to betray that trust,
so you mustn't do it.
Promise me, Emilia,
that you'll keep your promises from now on.
Yes... I will.
I'm sorry, Mother...
All right.
That's good enough.
And... what about you,
Geuse? Are you all right?
I-It was just such a dazzling sight...
I couldn't... I couldn't
hold back my tears...
Anyway, Emilia...
You mentioned fairies?
Oh, yeah! Fairies!
They've been coming to
help me for a long time!
Come on.
Are these... lesser spirits?!
And so many of them!
It would seem that Emilia-sama possesses
the natural talent to be a spirit user.
Lesser spirits? Natural talent
to be... a spirit user?
The things you call "fairies" are
beings called lesser spirits.
Those who communicate with them,
form contracts with them,
and borrow their powers are
known as spirit users.
And I can be one of those?
Hey, don't give her any weird ideas.
Emilia-sama will not
remain so young forever.
When no one is by her side,
in particular, they will be her strength.
But that could be dangerous,
and I can't let my sweet Emilia...
I'm on Geuse's side today!
I'm gonna be a spirit user! So there!
See? She's taken you seriously.
How will you take responsibility for this?
Well... I don't know what to...
Um...
What a dilemma.
You know, Mother Fortuna and Geuse,
you're acting like a mommy and daddy.
Wha—
D-Don't say silly things like that!
Geuse and I have known each other
for a long time! That's why—
That's right, Emilia-sama!
To one with a lifespan as long as mine,
even Fortuna-sama is basically a child.
Now, calling me child
is going a bit too far!
Do you even know how old I am?!
N-No, I didn't phrase that properly!
Of course, I'm quite aware
of your precise age,
and you are certainly too beautiful
and mature to be a child.
Indeed, indeed.
Very well, then. I'll forgive you.
But you'd better be very, very sorry.
Right...
At any rate, I've known Fortuna-sama
for a long, long time.
In fact, since the days when your
mother and father were well—
Geuse!
F-Forgive me.
My mother and father?
I'm sorry, Emilia.
We'll talk about that another time.
Go on back to your room.
Another time?
You'll really tell me, then?
Be a good girl. I know you can do that.
I'll let you see Geuse again soon, too.
You really, really mean it?
You promise? And you won't break it?
Yes. I promise.
It'll be a very, very important
promise between you and me.
All right, then.
I'll go back to my room now.
See you soon, Geuse.
Try not to cry too much.
That's a promise until we meet again.
Of course. We will meet again soon.
Someone's coming.
Who are you?
When you want to know someone's name,
isn't it common courtesy
to give your own first?
This is the first time we've
ever seen each other.
We should be on equal footing as far
as building a relationship goes,
so why do you get to demand my name
like you're so much better than me?
For a man, you sure seem
to like talking a lot.
"For a man"?
Thanks for showing me that you don't
even know any men to compare me to.
I can't just let that
attitude slide, you know.
You're disrespecting my individuality,
my authority—
That's enough!
Stop talking as if you're drunk on yourself!
Who are you?!
Archbishop of the Witch's Cult,
representing Greed...
Regulus Corneas.
A Journey Through Memories